Śrīla Guru Mahārāj will say, “How is it that the soul
Śrīla Guru Mahārāj说，
How can you go from the chit-jagat— the spiritual world—
怎么会从灵性世界脱离
and start experiencing the objective world?
来体验这个客观的世界？
[A Shadow Self of the Original Self]
真我的影子
It can’t, it’s not just suddenly that that will …
（灵魂的）那些能力不是突然获得的
that that capability and capacity is there.
而是原本就存在的
So, we introduce this concept chidābhās or chāyābhās, saying,
有个说法叫chidābhās或 chāyābhās
“The mind, the ego, intelligence, and senses
“由头脑、小我、智性和感官组成的自我
are a shadow self of the original self.”
是灵魂真我的影子”
That’s what it is. Chāyā means ‘shadow’.
Chāyā 意为阴影
Chāyābhās, chidābhās also means …
Chāyābhās, chidābhās
ābhās means ‘a semblance of something’.
ābhās 的意思是相似的
So, he’s saying, in this … it’s just like a glove, you could say.
举例来说，就像拿副手套来
The glove— you put a glove on your hand,
给手戴上手套
and you can handle certain things.
你就能做些特定的事情
Now we have a little more sophisticated
现在有了种更复杂的情况
so-called virtual reality.
叫虚拟现实
There’re some similarities there;
虽然有相似之处
virtual as oppose to substantial.
但虚拟依旧是跟本质相对的
So, Śrīla Guru Mahārāj said, “This shadow-like self,
所以，Śrīla Guru Mahārāj说，“这个影子
this shadow of the conscious self, enveloping the jīva soul,
意识真我的影子包裹着灵魂
allows it to navigate the objective world.”
让灵魂可以在这个客观世界里穿梭。”
So, we’re seeing through these eyes,
我们通过这些眼睛去看，
hearing, tasting, touching, smelling, feeling.
去听，品尝，触摸，闻和感受
So, as I said, the good news is
我说过，好消息是
this is indicative of the soul’s innate position.
这表明灵魂天生具有这些特质
Like, even in genetic engineering we find that
就像是即使在遗传学里
when they want to duplicate someone or something …
当要克隆复制生物的时候
Like, remember Dolly the sheep. Gurudev said something like,
还记得克隆羊多利吗，Gurudev有一次说
“When they all become Dolly, the world’s finished.” [Laughing]
“当周遭充斥着像多利一样的克隆生物，这个世界就走到尽头了”
So, there was the first sheep, genetically cloned sheep,
历史上第一只克隆羊
they called her Dolly.
叫 多利
But how did they do that?
是怎样克隆复制出来的呢？
This is what the point I mean to make.
我要说的观点来了
They get some genetic material.
他们拿一些基因材料
Genetic material means something very minute.
基因材料是些很微小的东西
This is the point I mean to make.
这是我想说的重点
DNA on a very minuscule,
DNA在非常非常微小的东西上记载着
on that plane that’s where the full identity is located.
全部个体信息都记录在上
That’s what I am trying to say.
这是我想提出的观点
we learn from this,
从中我们可以获得启示
is that identity, and I’m making a parallel here,
同样的
but within that plane there is the full spectral range of sensual expression:
但在那个层面里包含所有各种一系列的感官能力
seeing, hearing, tasting, touching, smelling, feeling.
看，听，品尝，触摸，闻，还有感觉
So, if this body is the biological expression of the soul’s delusion,
所以，如果说这个躯体是灵魂在错觉影响下表达出的生物形式
and it’s taking shape and myriads, and millions of forms.
他会以百万不计数的形体呈现
jala-jā nava-lakṣāṇi sthāvarā lakṣa-viṁśati
jala-jā nava-lakṣāṇi sthāvarā lakṣa-viṁśati
kṛmayo rudra-saṅkhyakāḥ (Padma Purāṇa)
kṛmayo rudra-saṅkhyakāḥ (Padma Purāṇa)
Just as you combine RGB or red, yellow, blue.
就像混合光的三原色，红黄蓝
Three makes nine,
3种颜色能调和出9种颜色
makes eighty one, eight point one,
再变81种
eight million four hundred thousand,
生物形式有840万种
millions of varieties of variations of life-forms
各式各样的生命
based upon tama, raja, sattva— ignorance, passion, goodness.
都是基于tama, raja, sattva— 愚昧、激情和善良属性
Millions of variations of that generate these varieties of life-forms.
这三种物质属性带来了百万种各种不同的生命形式
So, as the body is based upon exploiting tendencies,
躯体是由剥削性引发的
when we withdraw from the plane of exploitation
当我们从剥削的世界撤离
and become activated with dedicating tendency
启动奉爱
under the guidance of sādhu, śāstra, guru, Vaishnav,
在圣人、圣典、古茹和外士纳瓦的引领下
then the svarūp that you mentioned,
你的svarūp（真正身份）
it’s under construction.
将显示出来
It’s based upon dedicating tendencies.
那是基于奉献的趋向
So, as you can have a body here based upon the tendency to exploit,
就好比，在这个世界的躯体由剥削利用性引起的
the spiritual form is based upon the tendency to serve and dedicate.
灵性形体则是被奉献和服务驱动
The senses, the mind, the intelligence,
现在的感官、头脑、智力
according to Guru Mahārāj, all shadow representations
在Guru Mahārāj看来，
So, in Bhagavad-gītā we hear Kṛṣṇa’s saying,
在《博伽梵歌》中，奎师那说
bhūmir āpo ’nalo vāyuḥ khaṁ mano buddhir eva ca
bhūmir āpo ’nalo vāyuḥ khaṁ mano buddhir eva ca
ahaṅkāra itīyaṁ me bhinnā prakṛtir aṣṭadhā [Bg: 7.4]
ahaṅkāra itīyaṁ me bhinnā prakṛtir aṣṭadhā [Bg: 7.4]
“Earth, water, fire, air, ether, mind, intelligence and ego,” said,
土、水、火、气、以太、头脑、智力、小我
“these are My inferior energy.”
这些都是我的低级能量
Then He said, “And that so: mind, intelligence—inferior,
头脑智力是低等的
and jīva-bhūta—
jīva-bhūta
apareyam itas tv anyāṁ prakṛtiṁ viddhi me parām— [Bg: 7.5]
apareyam itas tv anyāṁ prakṛtiṁ viddhi me parām— [Bg: 7.5]
jīva is parā-prakṛti, superior energy to all of those things.”
jīva 灵魂是比所有那些都高等的能量
So, that means the mundane mind, the mundane intelligence,
那些物质性的头脑和智力
these mundane elements— they are covering jīva.
那些物质元素包裹着jīva（个体灵魂）
But jīva in her pristine glory has mind, intelligence, senses—everything.
但灵魂jiva在她本源的光辉世界里也有头脑，智力和感官等一切能力
And that we connect with them. What are we told?
我们要跟灵魂本源联结
hṛṣīkeṇa hṛṣīkeśa-sevanaṁ bhaktir ucyate [Nārada-pañcarātra]
hṛṣīkeṇa hṛṣīkeśa-sevanaṁ bhaktir ucyate [Nārada-pañcarātra]
By engaging the senses in the service of Kṛṣṇa,
将感官用于服务奎师那
that will awaken their natural serving tendency.
将唤醒我们自然天生的服务性
So that the mundane aspect gradually vanishes,
物质性的一面就会自动瓦解
diminishes and vanishes all together,
完全消失遁形
and the spiritual golden self comes out.
最后，灵性的金色真我显露出来